Today, PeopleMakeGames is in Michigan.
如今，PeopleMakeGames位于密歇根州。
I'm here to see Jerry Gretzinger because
我来这里是想见杰里·格雷茨格，因为
I want to see his map.
我想看看他的地图。
Jerry's map started as a doodle in the
杰瑞的地图最初是 20 世纪
early 1960s and although he did take
60 年代初的一张涂鸦，虽然他
what he now describes as a 20-year
后来有一段长达 20 年的“
coffee break, he's spent most of the
咖啡休息期”，但
decades since then adding to it and
此后几十年里，他
adding to it almost every single day. He
几乎每天都在不断地完善这张地图。 他
is now 84 and this map, made up of
现在 84 岁了，这张由
thousands of unique contiguous panels,
数千个独特的连续面板组成的地图
is his life's work. This isn't a map to
是他毕生的心血之作。 这不是一张通往
a real place. We knew that going in.
真实地点的地图。 我们一开始就知道这一点。但
What we didn't know is that over the
我们不知道的是，几
decades it had evolved into something
十年过去了，它已经完全演变成
else entirely. The map now has over
另一种东西了。 这张地图现在有超过
4,000 panels and I'm here to help Jerry
4000 个面板，我来这里是为了帮助杰瑞
assemble it for the first time in over
在 14 年多的时间里第一次把它组装起来
14 years. Isn't that right, Jerry?
。 杰瑞，你说得对吧？
&gt;&gt; Right.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; With the help of more than 20
在 20 多名
volunteers, we'd have 3 days to
志愿者的帮助下，我们将有 3 天时间像拼
construct Jerry's map like a vast
一个巨大的迷幻拼图一样，拼出杰瑞的地图
hallucinogenic jigsaw. But, our first
。 但我们的第一
stop was meeting Jerry and his wife Meg
站是去杰瑞和他的妻子梅格的
at their farm. So far, we'd only read
农场拜访他们。 到目前为止，我们只是读到
about Jerry's daily process, which is
过杰瑞的日常工作流程，那
like a ritual, and we wanted to watch it
就像一种仪式，我们想亲眼看看
firsthand.
。
&gt;&gt; You want to go up to the studio?
你想去工作室吗？
&gt;&gt; Absolutely.
绝对地。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; So, here's the thing about Jerry's map.
所以，关于杰瑞的地图，事情是这样的。
It's endless growth and regrowth is
它无休止的增长和再生是
dictated by a deck of cards that Jerry
由杰瑞不断调整的一副扑克牌决定的
is forever tinkering with. He flips a
。 他
card off the deck and has no choice but
从牌堆中翻出一张牌，别无选择，只能按照牌上的指示
to do what it says. The deck looks like
去做。 这甲板看起来像
it's haunted. It's forbidden to even
闹鬼一样。
shuffle it unless the deck orders you
除非牌组指示，否则禁止洗牌
to. [music]
。  [音乐]
&gt;&gt; I always draw from the bottom.
我总是从底部开始画。
&gt;&gt; So, we've got a 17 that reads
所以，我们有一个数字 17，它的意思是
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
[清嗓子]
&gt;&gt; "next higher dimension".
“下一个更高的维度”。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yep. [music] Yep. So, that's pretty
。  [音乐] 是的。 那真是太令人
exciting. I have to look behind you
兴奋了。 我得往你身后看一看
here. There's this calendar. There's the
。 这里有一份日历。 这是
last card that we worked on, North 22
我们处理的最后一张卡片，北纬 22 度，
East 29.
东经 29 度。
So, that's going to be the starting
所以，这将是我们的
point here. So, we're going to go down
起点。 所以，我们要向下移动
17 panels. One
17个面板。 一
&gt;&gt; Oh.
零。
&gt;&gt; two
二
three
三
&gt;&gt; Here, this little yellow dot is the
这里，这个黄色小点是
of this panel.
这个面板的中心。
And it also tells me what
它还会告诉我
level this panel is at.
这个面板处于哪个级别。
&gt;&gt; When you talk about levels, do you mean
当你谈到层次时，你指的是
like uh vert- levels of verticality?
垂直方向上的层次吗？
&gt;&gt; Sort of, yeah.
算是吧。
&gt;&gt; How would you describe it?
你会如何描述它？
&gt;&gt; Well, initially, it was um considered to
嗯，最初，它被认为
be other dimensions [music]
是现实的其他维度（音乐）
of reality.
。
&gt;&gt; Right, like three-dimensional space,
对，就像三维空间，
four-dimensional [music] space. Okay.
四维[音乐]空间。 好的。
&gt;&gt; It's It's more of a feeling
它更像是一张感觉
&gt;&gt; map has has moved from really literal
地图，已经从非常字面的
cartography
制图
&gt;&gt; [music]
（音乐）转变
&gt;&gt; to this other abstract form.
为另一种抽象形式。
&gt;&gt; Wait, does that mean you have a list of
等等，那是不是意味着你们有一份
what the different dimensions are?
不同维度的清单？
&gt;&gt; Yes,
是的，
&gt;&gt; [music]
这里有音乐。
So,
所以，
um we've gone
嗯，我们已经经历了
through blank the blank page, [music]
空白的页面，[音乐]
we've gone through the paint level
我们已经经历了绘画阶段，
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; and we're This panel is at the 1-in
而我们……这个面板位于 1 英寸
square collage.
见方的拼贴画中。
&gt;&gt; So, we're doing we're we're beginning a
所以，我们现在正在地图上开始绘制一座
city on this map.
城市。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. [music]
。  [音乐] 是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; These folders all contain collage
这些文件夹里都装有拼贴
material.
材料。
&gt;&gt; Cool. This is a mix of real maps. Like
凉爽的。 这是真实地图的混合体。
this is the back This is the back of the
这是地图的背面
map.
。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; And then but then this is stuff you
然后，但这就是你
illustrated and
举例说明的东西，
&gt;&gt; Right.
没错。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Now, the 17 is significant. We're
。 现在，数字 17 意义非凡。 我们
going to start at that point, [music]
将从这一点开始（音乐），
but we're going to add 17 blocks.
但我们会添加 17 个模块。
&gt;&gt; Hm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait. Wait.
等等。 等待。 等待。 等待。 等待。 等待。
Wait. How did
等待。
&gt;&gt; You didn't think about that you?
你怎么能没想到这一点呢？
&gt;&gt; No. No, I attempt to think as little as
不，我尽量少去思考
as possible.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; I want it to be as random as possible. I
我希望结果尽可能随机。 我
don't close my eyes when I put it down,
放下书的时候不会闭上眼睛，
but I might as well.
但其实闭上眼睛也无妨。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; I just slap it on.
我就直接抹上去。   太
&gt;&gt; That's mad That's that's the first thing
疯狂了！这是
I've seen today that's really
我今天看到的第一件让
distressing to me.
我感到非常不安的事情。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; We just put down [music]
我们刚刚在
5 10
5 到 10 个
&gt;&gt; city blocks.
街区内播放了 [音乐]。
&gt;&gt; So, we need to put down seven more.
所以，我们还需要再放下七个。
&gt;&gt; of that. That represents 400 people.
就是那件事。 那相当于400人。
[music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; In previous decades, Jerry used the
在之前的几十年里，杰瑞一直用
map's total population as a measure of
地图上的总人口数来衡量
how much time had passed within his
他的世界中过去了多少时间
world, but he stopped because as the map
，但他后来停止了这种做法，因为随着地图
got more complex, the system started to
变得越来越复杂，这个系统开始
come apart at the seams.
分崩离析。
&gt;&gt; Hm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; It's very red where they live.
他们居住的地方一片红色。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah, I don't know what's going on
。 是啊，我不知道
there.
那里发生了什么事。
&gt;&gt; is a sort of I read this as like a sort
我把它理解为一种
of toxic river.
有毒的河流。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. [clears throat]
。  [清嗓子]
Okay.
好的。
We only want 17, so
我们只需要 17 个，所以
1 5 6
1 5 6 是的
Yeah, I'm going to uh
，我打算
throw a park in there.
在那里加一个公园。
So, with that, I'm going to complete
这样，我就能完成这座
the new
新城的建设了
town.
。
Well, I better put the park next to the
嗯，我最好把公园建在
center here.
中心旁边。
&gt;&gt; I worry you're thinking, though.
不过，我担心你在想什么。
You told me
你告诉我
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; I know. I know. I know. I know. I know.
我知道。 我知道。 我知道。 我知道。 我知道。
I know.
我知道。
Well, part of me can't resist. Now,
嗯，我有点无法抗拒。 现在，
it's a brand new town. We have to find a
这里已是一座全新的城镇。 我们得给它
name for it.
起个名字。
&gt;&gt; Oh.
哦。   这其中有
&gt;&gt; And there's a whole process for that.
一整套流程。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Yep. Okay.
是的。 好的。
&gt;&gt; So, these are all town names, but some
所以，这些都是城镇名称，但有些
towns have been [music] eliminated by
城镇已经被虚空所抹去
the void.
。
So, we don't need
所以，我们不再需要
their
他们的
their out names anymore. What I need to
外号了。 我需要
find is a name that doesn't exist that
找到的是一个不存在的名字，因为
the town doesn't exist anymore. Let's
那个城镇已经不存在了。 我们
try Norvin.
试试诺文吧。
&gt;&gt; Norvin's on the it's used.
Norvin's on the used.   是的
&gt;&gt; Yep. So, that's no good.
。 所以，这可不好。   如果是
&gt;&gt; No Poof.
No Poof 呢？
&gt;&gt; He wanted to be involved.
他想参与其中。
&gt;&gt; No, that's that's uh
不，那根本
&gt;&gt; That's no exist.
不存在。
Roslyn's there.
罗丝琳在那里。
&gt;&gt; Quinston's nice.
昆斯顿人很好。
&gt;&gt; Hansel
汉塞尔，
&gt;&gt; What do you think of Quinston?
你觉得昆斯顿怎么样？
&gt;&gt; Quinston?
昆斯顿？
&gt;&gt; It was a
那是一声“
&gt;&gt; Hey.
嘿”。
&gt;&gt; No, I just thought it was under
不，我只是以为它正在
consideration.
考虑中。
&gt;&gt; Hansel
汉塞尔
&gt;&gt; going for it.
放手一搏。
&gt;&gt; Wimptown.
温普敦。
Wimptown. Wimptown.
温普敦。 温普敦。
There, see?
看到了吗？
&gt;&gt; It's been eliminated.
它已被消除。
&gt;&gt; Wimptown
温普敦，
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
没错。
&gt;&gt; was smothered by void 206 in 1646.
1646年被206号虚空吞噬。
&gt;&gt; Wow.
哇。
&gt;&gt; So,
那么，
&gt;&gt; Would they would the people make a new
他们会建造一个新的
Wimptown? No.
温普镇吗？ 不。
&gt;&gt; Uh would they have tried?
呃，他们会尝试吗？
But that didn't work out very well.
但结果并不理想。
&gt;&gt; No, but if Wimptown was eliminated and
不，但是如果温普镇被取消，
we're building a new town, could this be
我们正在建造一个新城镇，这会不会是……
&gt;&gt; It could be
这会不会是
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
（清嗓子）
&gt;&gt; a new Wimptown.
一个新的温普镇。
&gt;&gt; Well, it could be if it were in a
嗯，如果是在
different dimension, probably.
另一个维度的话，或许就有可能了。
But this isn't the same old dimension
但这和
that the original Wimptown [music] was.
最初的 Wimptown [音乐] 的维度已经不一样了。
And the folks who lived in the old
而居住在老温
Wimptown have been transported into
普镇的人们则被传送到了
another dimension.
另一个维度。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes. So, these people do they do these
。 所以，这些人会这样做，这些
people
人会这样做。
Okay, I think I'm following. These
好的，我想我明白了。 这些
people don't know
人不知道吗？
Do they know about the original
他们知道最初的
Wimptown?
温普镇吗？
&gt;&gt; Uh they might.
嗯，他们或许会。
They would read history books.
他们会读历史书。
&gt;&gt; Got you.
抓到你了。
&gt;&gt; There's a theory that the the map is
有一种理论认为，这张地图
essentially a human zoo.
本质上是一个人类动物园。
&gt;&gt; Uh
呃，那是
that higher beings from we don't know
来自我们不知道的更高层次的生物
where
。
&gt;&gt; have created this to resemble
将其设计成类似
human habitat. [music]
人类居住环境的样子。  [音乐]，里面
it is populated with reanimated humans
居住着
from
来自
Earth.
地球的复活人类。
&gt;&gt; Got you.
抓到你了。
&gt;&gt; Right.
正确的。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Someone dies,
有人死了，
they come in their spaceship and they
他们乘坐宇宙飞船来了，
&gt;&gt; But the
但是……
Okay, but would the humans in [music]
好吧，但是动物园里的人类还会继续
the zoo still be breeding?
繁殖吗？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes.
。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; They're They're reanimated.
他们复活了。
Reanimated. They're just
复活了。 它们又被
brought to life again. The deal but the
赋予了新的生命。 协议
deal is they live at the same age they
是这样的，但他们现在的年龄和他们小时候一样大
&gt;&gt; Oh.
。
&gt;&gt; They just stay
他们就待在那里。
&gt;&gt; You say there's a theory. Is it the
你说有一种理论。 是
theory? Do you have multiple theories?
理论问题吗？ 你还有其他理论吗？
principal theory about the map is that
关于这张地图还有另一种主要理论，那就是
it's a two-dimensional actually a
它实际上是一个
two-dimensional place.
二维空间。
&gt;&gt; flatland.
平原。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; So that [music] these two-dimensional
这样，这些二维的
people can look at this map and see
人就可以看着这张地图，知道
where they are because they as the Since
自己在哪里，因为
they only have two dimensions, they
他们只有二维，所以他们
can't really see
实际上看不到
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
东西。   他们
&gt;&gt; anything around them.
周围的一切。
&gt;&gt; Okay, but the map Okay.
好的，但是地图没问题。
Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; Webtown
Webtown
is at north 21 west 20
位于北纬21度西经20度，
and it was created in 1663
创建于1663年，
and the population
人口
is
为
7,600.
7600人。
&gt;&gt; Okay. And then the card gets placed back
好的。 然后这张牌被放回
in the deck.
牌堆。
&gt;&gt; Back on top and we go into the next one.
回到顶部，我们进入下一个。
Oh, it's another 17.
哦，又是17。
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
[清嗓子]
&gt;&gt; doing another card today.
今天还要再出一张牌。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; As we flipped through the map, I noticed
当我们翻阅地图时，我注意到
more and more panels where Jerry had
越来越多的石板上，杰瑞把
buried his own art. Some of it decades
自己的艺术作品埋了起来。 有些方案酝酿了几十年，一直隐藏在
in the making under white paper. Like an
白纸黑字之下。 就像
a theory on natural disasters, Jerry
关于自然灾害的理论一样，杰瑞把这
refers to this as the void. And now, he
称为虚空。 现在，他也
was starting to populate this as well,
开始往这里填充一些东西，
but with something else.
但填充的是别的东西。
&gt;&gt; These are
这些是
notes people have written to me. Some
别人写给我的留言。 有些
are journals of mine.
是我的日记。
A lot of it is me at my age trying to
很多作品都是我这个年纪想要
record my life.
记录自己的生活。
&gt;&gt; Oh.
哦。
&gt;&gt; I I because I you know, I save things. I
因为你知道，我喜欢保存东西。 我
spent 3 years at the University of
在密歇根大学待了三年
Michigan.
。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; [music]
我在安娜堡学习音乐，然后
from
从
Ann Arbor to Berkeley. All my friends,
安娜堡转学到伯克利。 我的所有朋友，
close friends, were back in Ann Arbor,
亲密的朋友，都回到了安娜堡，
so we And this was the 1960s, so we
所以我们……那是 20 世纪 60 年代，所以我们互相
wrote letters back and forth.
写信。
&gt;&gt; Oh.
哦。
&gt;&gt; And I saved those letters.
我把那些信件都保存了下来。
&gt;&gt; Are you Are you Are you cutting up the
你是不是在剪裁
originals?
原件？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I am.
，我是。
&gt;&gt; Oh, that's Is that bittersweet, or does
哦，这让人感到一丝苦涩，还是
he not care?
他根本不在乎？
&gt;&gt; A little bit.
一点点。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
That's really interesting. So, the void
这真有意思。 所以，虚空
is is actually made up of your
实际上是由你的……是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's the the void. [music]
，那就是虚空。  [音乐]
The initial level of the void is
虚空的初始层
basically white or off-white.
基本上是白色或灰白色。
&gt;&gt; And then you kind of develop it into
然后你把它发展成……
&gt;&gt; And then there's a second level that's
然后还有第二层，
all black and white print.
全是黑白印刷品。   当
when you destroy all the letters that
你销毁所有收集到的信件时，
That's quite touching and sad.
那真是令人感动又悲伤。
&gt;&gt; It's It's a way for me to preserve it.
这是我保存它的一种方式。
&gt;&gt; Did it used to be more like a real
以前是不是更像真的？是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; place?
地方？   是的
&gt;&gt; When When did that change?
这种情况是什么时候改变的？
&gt;&gt; Um
嗯，
in the '80s. [music]
在80年代。  [音乐]
Started with the
从
limbs. That was a real
四肢开始。 那对
radical breakthrough for me. Sticking
我来说真是一次意义重大的突破。 把
them on [music] collage style.
它们贴上去，做成音乐拼贴画。
Every time I make a change in the rules,
每次我修改规则（
&gt;&gt; [music]
音乐），
&gt;&gt; I make a note of it in here.
我都会在这里做个记录。
&gt;&gt; Oh my god.
我的天啊。
I spent 10, 11, 12 years of my life. I'm
我花了10年、11年、12年的时间。 我
still kind of doing it for a living,
仍然以这为生，
like basically reading rulebooks.
基本上就是阅读规则手册。   对
This to me is like
我来说，这就像是……
This has so much um
这里面蕴含着很多……嗯……
like anima, uh like energy.
灵魂，呃……能量。
&gt;&gt; Everywhere you looked, there was another
放眼望去，到处都是另一个
system. The map could only be painted
系统。 这张地图只能
using a palette of colors that was
使用经过
strictly remixed, then recorded. At one
严格重新混合并记录的调色板来绘制。 有一段
point, Jerry had an entire league of
时间，杰瑞
sports teams existing in world and would
在现实世界中建立了一个完整的体育联盟，并
simulate games between them using yet
使用另一个系统来模拟这些球队之间的比赛
another system.
。
&gt;&gt; I'm going to be honest, Jerry. This map
杰瑞，我实话实说。 这张地图
seems like a lot of work.
看起来工作量很大。
&gt;&gt; It is.
这是。   确实如此
It is, but um
，但是，嗯，
I like doing it.
我喜欢这样做。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; I like doing it because it's full of
我喜欢做这件事，因为它充满了
surprises.
惊喜。
&gt;&gt; It might not surprise you to know that
你可能不会感到惊讶，
Jerry's love of systems has found its
杰瑞对系统的热爱也渗透到了
way into the rest of his life as well.
他生活的其他方面。
&gt;&gt; Well, there's the old clothing [music]
嗯，还有以前的服装（音乐）那
thing.
件事。   嗯，
I've kind of abandoned that. But in
我已经放弃那个计划了。 但在
even-numbered months, [music] I would
偶数月份，我会
wear all solid colored clothes. And in
穿纯色的衣服。
odd-numbered months, all patterns.
奇数月份则全部都是某种模式。
&gt;&gt; Right. Okay.
正确的。 好的。
&gt;&gt; It was difficult to find pattern [music]
很难找到图案[音乐]
pants
裤子
or shoes.
或鞋子。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Not socks. Socks are [music]
不是袜子。 袜子是[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Socks are fine. Yeah.
袜子很好。 是的。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
Um
嗯
So, I kind of quit that. But yeah, and
，所以我就放弃了那份工作。 是的，
then when it comes to the farm,
说到农场，
I have trails. We'll see some of those.
我这里有小径。 我们会看到其中一些。
Odd-numbered days of the month, we go
每月单数日，我们
counterclockwise.
逆时针方向进行。
&gt;&gt; [clears throat]
[清嗓子]
&gt;&gt; And and numbered, we go clockwise. I do
然后，我们按顺序编号，顺时针方向进行。 我做
everything as though I'm going to live
任何事都像我会
forever.
永远活下去一样。
Um
嗯，
and that's probably not going to happen,
这可能不会发生，
but [laughter]
但是（笑）
it's a nice approach, I think.
我觉得这是一个不错的想法。
&gt;&gt; Inside this man was a mischievous and
这个人内心深处是一位顽皮而
chaotic artist, but one who found
混乱的艺术家，但他却在
comfort in tying himself up with rules.
规则的束缚中找到了慰藉。
It was a pleasure to spend time with
和他在一起的时光令人愉快
him, which was a relief, as we were
，也让人松了一口气，因为
about to spend the next 3 days
接下来的三天我们都要跪在地上
assembling his work on our hands and
组装他的作品
knees.
。
Day one, the best local venue big enough
第一天，当地最适合
to construct Jerry's map was the
搭建杰瑞地图的场地是
Strongheart Center, a community space
强心中心，这是一个
belonging to the Grand Traverse Band of
属于大特拉弗斯
Ottawa and Chippewa Indians, whose
渥太华和奇佩瓦印第安部落的社区空间，该
tribal council had been kind enough to
部落委员会非常友好地
allow us to do something that even we
允许我们做一些连我们自己都
didn't fully understand. It wasn't lost
不太明白的事情。
on us that this was a pretty special
我们很清楚，这里是
place to lay out Jerry's map, and we
展示杰瑞地图的一个非常特别的地方，我们
once again for inviting us into that
再次感谢大特拉弗斯乐队邀请我们来到这只
giant turtle resting here on the shore
栖息在五大湖岸边的巨龟的领地
of the Great Lakes.
。
How you feeling?
你感觉怎么样？
&gt;&gt; Good.
好的。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah?
？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。   是的
Nervous at all?
紧张吗？   是的
&gt;&gt; Yes.
。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Very.
好的。 非常。
Oh, very nervous. That
哦，好紧张。 是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; What I mean, what could possibly go
我的意思是，组装 4100 件产品能出什么
wrong with assembling 4,100 Nothing at
问题呢？根本不会出问题
all. See, that's what we're talking
。 你看，这就是我们说的
about. We had access to an entire
。 我们可以使用整个
basketball court, and by our
篮球场，据我们
estimations, it would be just big
估计，它的大小刚刚
enough. When you look at it like that,
够用。 这样看来，好像也
it doesn't look that bad.
没那么糟糕。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。   开始
Let's get to work.
工作吧。   我们
At our disposal, we had one Nick,
手头只有尼克（
Jerry's assistant who'd actually come up
杰瑞的助手，他确实想出了
with a plan, 20 volunteers with no plan
一个计划）、20名没有计划的志愿者
working a shift system, maybe like eight
轮班工作、大约8个
knee pads, only two of these special
护膝、只有两根特制的
sticks, which would not be enough, and
棍子（这肯定不够），以及
quite literally 9,000
9000张
stickers to gum the whole thing to the
贴纸，用来把整个装置粘在
floor. And basically, what we had to do
地板上。 基本上，我们所要做的
is assemble one mega perfectly spaced
就是组装一个间距完美的巨型
grid.
网格。
&gt;&gt; This is the hardest part of the whole
这是整件事中最难的部分
thing.
。
&gt;&gt; Once Meg placed our first all-important
梅格安装好我们第一批至关重要的
panels, we were underway.
面板后，我们就正式开始了。
&gt;&gt; Meg, if you want to save your knees,
梅格，如果你也想保护你的膝盖，
too, we got we got some nice knees.
我们得说，我们的膝盖都很好。
&gt;&gt; I know.
我知道。
&gt;&gt; She's in the zone.
她进入了最佳状态。
&gt;&gt; She's in the zone. We don't want to mess
她进入了最佳状态。 我们不想去碰
with it.
它。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, except that people are already
是啊，只不过现在
wrecking my zone.
我的地盘已经被别人糟蹋了。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Fun thing about Jerry's map, we were
杰瑞的地图很有趣，我们
starting our build from the dead center,
从正中心开始建造，
which is the most urban map-like part.
而正中心是最像城市地图的部分。
It's the closest look we'd get at what
这是我们能了解到的
this world used to be. From here, things
这个世界过去模样的最接近的途径。 从这里开始，事情
would only get stranger.
只会变得更加离奇。
&gt;&gt; It's very satisfying.
非常令人满意。
And I can tell
我知道
shredded tomorrow
明天演出进行到
when we're a third of the way through.
三分之一的时候，我的背肯定会因为听音乐而疼痛难忍。
&gt;&gt; These poster mats come on little sheets
这些海报垫是一小张一小张的，
and the backing has to be peeled off.
需要把背纸撕掉。
&gt;&gt; [crying]
[哭泣]
&gt;&gt; Very tedious.
太无聊了。
But I'm pretty used to it by now.
但我现在已经相当习惯了。
&gt;&gt; It's not a competition. It's not. This
这不是一场比赛。 它不是。 这
is a beautiful collaborative art
是一个美妙的合作艺术
construction process. But if it was a
创作过程。 但如果这是一场
competition, I would have just nailed
比赛，我肯定能比他们中的
the east-west parallel faster than any
任何一个人更快地找到东西向的纬线
of these guys. With a couple of rows
。 铺开几行之后
laid out, the map was starting to take
，地图开始逐渐
shape. Look at that. Only 4,000 panels
成形。 瞧瞧。 还剩下4000块面板
left to go. We're really at the edge of
待安装。 我们现在真的已经到了
existence over here, aren't we? This is
生存的边缘了，不是吗？ 这就是
This is like where reality starts to
现实开始
break down.
崩塌的地方。
Like it's all so civilized over there
感觉那里的一切都那么文明，
and then
然后，是的
&gt;&gt; Yes.
。
&gt;&gt; This is like Yeah, yeah, yeah.
这就像是“是是是”。
&gt;&gt; Chaos.
混乱。
&gt;&gt; This was the first time I'd seen panels
这是我第一次看到画板
laid out consecutively and I was shocked
连续排列，我震惊地发现
at how much of Jerry's own work had been
杰瑞自己的作品竟然有那么多被
eaten by that white void. And maybe my
那片空白吞噬了。 也许我
focus wandered a bit.
有点走神了。
&gt;&gt; Um I found S3 too. So this should be
嗯，我也找到了S3。 所以这里应该放这个，
here and then it's like, yeah. So we're
然后就变成了，是的。 所以我们
just going to very quickly remove the
很快就要删除“
I was working so fast.
我当时工作得非常快”这句话了。
I've lost its stick.
我的棍子丢了。
This isn't a filmable moment. If Jerry
这不是一个适合拍摄的瞬间。 如果杰瑞
hadn't made it so abstract, it would be
没有把画面做得这么抽象，那么
obvious when the panels didn't line up.
当各个面板没有对齐时，就会很明显了。
But because he's a [__] artist, it's
但因为他是个艺术家，所以有
possible to make make and not know.
可能创作出来却不自知。
Jerry, how are we doing, do you think?
杰瑞，你觉得我们做得怎么样？
&gt;&gt; We're doing great.
我们做得很好。
We're doing too well.
我们做得太好了。
&gt;&gt; I'm doing well. You're just sort of
我一切都好。 你只是
standing there. You're just kind of
站在那里。 你真是……
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
（笑）
&gt;&gt; It's amazing what a human can do just
人类只要一点一点地努力，就能取得惊人的成就
working a little bit at a time.
。
&gt;&gt; You know, twice I've sold panels to two
你知道吗，我两次把这幅画卖给了两位
different women and they wrote me back
不同的女士，她们都给我回信
and said, "I bought [music] this for my
说：“我买这幅画是送给我
husband. He's a writer.
丈夫的。他是个作家。
I just show him what [music] persistence
我只是想让他看看坚持不懈能带来什么。”哇哦。是的。
And same story from the two different
两位女士的经历都一样
women. One was in Iowa and one was in
。一位在爱荷华州，一位在
Australia.
澳大利亚。
&gt;&gt; And both had the idea of buying it for
她们都想买这幅画送给
their partner to [music] show if you
自己的伴侣，让他看看
stick at something.
坚持不懈能带来什么。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。这算是
&gt;&gt; That's kind of one way to look at this
看待这幅画的一种方式
map, isn't it? It's like, you know, they
，不是吗？就像，你知道，人们常说
say it takes
要花
&gt;&gt; [music]
一万个小时
to become an expert or whatever.
才能成为专家什么的。没错。
&gt;&gt; Right.
但是，如果你把
something for your entire life?
一生都投入到某件事上呢？
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; I mean, I also think that that this map
我的意思是，我也觉得这幅画
looks incredible, but just looking at it
看起来很棒，但仅仅看它并
doesn't reflect the fact that you've
不能反映出你一遍又一遍地
erased and rebuilt and erased and
擦除、重建、擦除、
rebuilt and erased and rebuilt. So, it's
重建、擦除、重建的事实。所以，这
like it's exponentially to view the map
幅画的意义是指数级的。要
properly, you'd actually Okay, that's
真正理解它，你实际上会……好吧， 那是
the next people my games video. We do
我下一个游戏视频的内容。我们会
the map in 3D space
在3D空间里制作地图。
&gt;&gt; Okay, yeah.
好的，是的。这样
&gt;&gt; to show the layers over time as well.
也能展示不同图层随时间的变化。
&gt;&gt; Oh, yes.
哦，是的。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Okay, good.
好的，不错。
Work continued smoothly that afternoon
那天下午工作进展顺利，
until I announced we were missing a
直到我宣布我们少了一块
panel when we weren't. I It's tragic cuz
面板，而实际上并没有。真是太糟糕了，因为
I sent up the alarm that the panel was
我发出了面板
missing. I actually had failed to
丢失的警报。实际上，我没能把
separate [music] two pieces of paper. I
[音乐]两张纸分开。我
think I gained a lot of credibility from
觉得我今天早上努力工作赢得了不少信任
how hard I worked this morning.
。
Um there was also a moment where I was
嗯，还有一次，是我
the one who said that the initial
指出最初的
vertical column was off center.
垂直柱偏离了中心。
And I think that again bought me a lot
我觉得那又让我赢得了不少
of kudos.
赞誉。不过，
I think I've
我觉得我
just lost some of it.
刚刚失去了一些。
&gt;&gt; Slightly ashamed, I thought this was a
有点不好意思，
good time for me to stretch my back out
我想趁着
and make the most of us being in a
我们在
gymnasium.
体育馆，好好伸展一下背部，充分利用一下。
&gt;&gt; You know, all kind of like neck and
你知道，就是做做颈肩
shoulders, upper back
、上背，
&gt;&gt; Oh, look at that.
哦，看看这个。
&gt;&gt; spine and trunk, mid back and spine,
脊柱和躯干、中背和脊柱、
lower back and spine.
下背和脊柱。
&gt;&gt; I'd never seen this device before in my
我这辈子都没见过这种器械
life. I still haven't. I think it might
。我仍然 还没有。我觉得这可能
be the only one on earth.
是地球上唯一一个。
&gt;&gt; You know, one of my mentors when I was
你知道，我刚入行做游戏记者的时候，我的一位导师
coming up as a games journalist said,
说过，
you can have talent
你可以有天赋，
or you can have just a total lack of
也可以完全没有
dignity.
尊严。
&gt;&gt; [snorts]
[嗤笑]
&gt;&gt; I chose both.
我两者都选了。
&gt;&gt; And with that, we placed our final
就这样，我们完成了
panels of day one.
第一天的最后几块拼图。
I'm going to wake up tomorrow morning
明天早上醒来，我要泡个
and I'm going to have a hot bath in my
热水澡放松一下，
back and
然后
we're going to do it again until it's
我们再继续，直到
finished.
完成为止。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; But before we come back for day two,
但在第二天开始之前，
let's give you a proper look at
让我们好好看看你
something you've only seen a peek of so
之前只瞥见过一眼的东西——
far, Jerry's deck of cards, the arcane
杰瑞的卡牌，这个神秘的
object that powers all of this. Not only
物件驱动着这一切。
does it look like the cursed plaything
它不仅看起来像是某个
of a trickster god, it actually handles
恶作剧之神的诅咒玩物，实际上还负责
Jerry's admin. The deck is what tells
杰瑞的日常管理。这副卡牌指示
him to scan panels, preserving different
他扫描拼图，保存
eras of the map. And these days it also
地图的不同时期。最近，它还
tells him to go and journal. Jerry hates
指示他去写日记。杰瑞讨厌
journaling and often ignores this card
写日记，所以经常无视这张牌
when it comes up.
。“
&gt;&gt; Make blanks.
留空。”
When I say blank, I refer to these. Uh
当我 我说空白，我指的是这些。哦
&gt;&gt; Oh, wait, these are These are These are
，等等，这些是……这些是……这些是
going to be map tiles.
地图板块。是的。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Wait, so like on the edge of the map
等等，就像在地图边缘……
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; you just slot on something that looks
你只要把看起来
super complete.
非常完整的东西放上去就行了。等
&gt;&gt; You'll see when we lay it all out.
我们全部摆出来你就知道了。
&gt;&gt; we lay it all out. Okay. Okay. Okay.
我们全部摆出来。好的。好的。好的。是的。泼墨。嗯，
&gt;&gt; spatter. Well, then yours is a little
那你的就是一点
spatter.
泼墨。是的。是的。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. in the world. putting
。在世界里……把
ink spatter on
墨水泼上去……是的。是的。哦
Oh, there's a quick shuffle.
，快速洗牌。
&gt;&gt; Quick shuffle deck.
快速洗牌。
Silk screening panels.
丝网印刷面板。
&gt;&gt; Oh, this is the one for Meg. This panel
哦，这是给梅格的。这个面板
and the eight surrounding ones I can put
和周围的八个面板我可以
in an envelope and give them to Meg
放在信封里给梅格。
&gt;&gt; Oh.
哦。
&gt;&gt; silk screened.
丝网印刷的。哦
&gt;&gt; And that's her choice.
。
&gt;&gt; Cool.
酷。
&gt;&gt; Oh, oh, this has to do with the paints.
哦，哦，这和颜料有关。
This has to do with my thinking the
这和我认为
paints were becoming too
颜料变得
&gt;&gt; Too dark.
太暗有关。
&gt;&gt; dark and murky.
太暗太浑浊了。
&gt;&gt; And then yeah, so you got a new white
然后，是的，所以你得到了一种新的
color. That's clever.
白色。这很聪明。
This is game balance. That's what you're
这是为了游戏平衡。这就是你……
doing.
正在做。
&gt;&gt; yes, yes. Let me explain that to you.
是的，是的。让我给你解释一下。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
嗯。泼
Spatter.
溅。
&gt;&gt; More spatter.
更多泼溅。
&gt;&gt; these cards are so Look at Look at this.
这些牌真棒。看看这个。
Look how cool that is.
看看这多酷。
That's awesome.
太棒了。
&gt;&gt; Well, the longer in that they're in the
嗯，它们在
pack, [music] the more they get added to
牌堆里待的时间越长，[音乐]它们就会被添加得越多，
them cuz they Every time it comes up, I
因为每次出现的时候，我
usually add something. Uh
通常都会添加一些东西。呃，
&gt;&gt; Shuffle deck thoroughly.
彻底洗牌。
&gt;&gt; Thorough. Yes, that's one card at a
彻底。是的，一次一张牌
time.
。
&gt;&gt; Color.
颜色。
&gt;&gt; No color.
没有颜色。
&gt;&gt; That's just the nine of spades.
那只是黑桃九。
We just We just blotted you up.
我们只是……我们只是把你弄脏了。
Uh
呃，
Journal.
日记。
Scan
扫描
for overlays.
叠加层。
&gt;&gt; Oh, overlays.
哦，叠加层。叠加层
&gt;&gt; The overlays are these
就是这种
kinds of sheets like that.
纸。
&gt;&gt; Ooh.
哦。是的
Yes.
。
&gt;&gt; And And so, I'll put this in the printer
然后，我会把它放进打印机里
and print it.
打印出来。
&gt;&gt; Oh, you put
哦，你放……
&gt;&gt; Usually
通常
&gt;&gt; I pop up I've seen panels that you've
我会弹出……我见过你这样
done this. There's something underneath
做的面板。下面有一些东西，
that you just like
你就像
put a hole
打了个洞一样。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, so I'll take one of the collage
是的，所以我拿一张拼
sheets.
贴纸。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, yeah, yeah. And then
是的，是的，是的。然后
&gt;&gt; And put it in the printer and print it.
把它放进打印机里打印出来。
Print this on top of it.
打印这个 在上面。往
&gt;&gt; Add one card to the deck.
牌堆里加一张牌。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and I have spare cards down there.
是的，我下面还有备用牌。
There's the one that says add two cards.
有一张写着加两张牌。
&gt;&gt; And there's one that says
还有一张写着……
uh deduct two cards.
减两张牌。
&gt;&gt; Oh.
哦。
&gt;&gt; So, I don't I don't know. It's stayed
所以，我不知道。它的
[music] about the same size.
大小基本没变。大概
It's around 100 Well, over 100.
100左右，嗯，超过100。
&gt;&gt; Take next city panel to high dimension.
把下一个城市面板放到高维度。是的
Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; Uh, when it's checkerboard of neutrals.
呃，当它是中性色的棋盘格时。
What was I thinking?
我当时在想什么？
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; 1-in checkerboard of
1英寸的
neutrals.
中性色棋盘格。
Boy, that comes up and I've been
哎呀，这出现了，我一直……
&gt;&gt; You're in trouble.
你麻烦了。
That's your favorite
那是你最喜欢的……
&gt;&gt; Uh, uh, high dimension, 1-in collage.
呃，呃，高维度，1英寸拼贴画。
Add one panel, new color.
加一个面板，新颜色。
&gt;&gt; Next high dimension, 8x4.
下一个高维度，8x4。
&gt;&gt; beginning [clears throat]
开始[清嗓子]
&gt;&gt; Wait, you can do high dimensions in the
等等，你可以在虚空中做高维度
voids?
？
&gt;&gt; And so
所以，
&gt;&gt; There's white and then there's your
有白色，然后是你的
memory layer.
记忆层。是的
&gt;&gt; That Yeah.
。
&gt;&gt; And then
然后……
&gt;&gt; And then there's a city layer.
然后是城市层。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好的。
&gt;&gt; We didn't see any of those today.
我们没看到 今天那些地方都没有。
&gt;&gt; No.
不，
&gt;&gt; They're void cities.
它们是虚空之城。
We think that's where those reanimated
我们认为那些复活的
folks get shipped to.
人会被送到那里。他们会被送到那里。是的
&gt;&gt; to.
。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. The term for this in the games
。在游戏
industry, like the meaning behind
行业，这指的是某种东西背后的含义，也就是
what's really going on. We call that
故事的真正意义。我们称之为背景故事
lore.
。
&gt;&gt; Oh.
哦，
&gt;&gt; L O R E. So, like
背景故事。所以，就像，
&gt;&gt; What we would say in the games industry
在游戏行业，我们会说
is that Jerry's map has lore and the
杰瑞的地图有背景故事，而
lore is that
背景故事是，
actually
实际上
people are dying and then they are
有人死去，然后
reanimated in the void cities and that's
在虚空之城里复活，这没
&gt;&gt; Okay.
问题。
&gt;&gt; And then people get really excited about
然后人们对
lore and um
背景故事非常感兴趣，嗯，背景
&gt;&gt; A lore. Okay. Yeah, that's cool.
故事。好的。是的，很酷。
&gt;&gt; It is. Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; I I like knowing that term.
我喜欢了解这个术语。
&gt;&gt; I cannot overstate how much it's not the
我必须强调，
map that Jerry is designing, but this
杰瑞设计的不是地图，而是这套
deck. The map is just him being bossed
牌组。地图只是他被
have made 13 years ago. Interestingly
13年前可能做出的那些疯狂决定所左右的结果。有趣的
though, as a young man, Jerry actually
是，杰瑞年轻时实际上
went to school for architecture and you
学过建筑，你
can see it in the earliest records of
可以在地图最早的记录中看到这一点
the map. Right, enough of that. Back to
。 好了，就说到这儿吧。回到
the build.
搭建工作。今天是
It's day two.
第二天，
It's Sunday. The gym is closed, but
星期天。健身房关门了，但
we're here putting in work.
我们还在加班。
We did the final count yesterday and we
昨天我们做了最终统计，
just 35% of the map.
地图只完成了35%。
That's not great. A lot of us are really
这可不太妙。我们很多人都浑身
achy.
酸痛，
Spines giving out. We resemble prawns.
脊椎都快断了，像虾一样。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; I would love to end today
我希望今天能完成
on like 72%.
72%。
That'll be good going into the third
这样就能顺利进入第三
most painful day.
痛苦的一天了。
Let's see if we get there.
看看我们能不能做到吧。又过了
After another couple of hours, I was
几个小时，我
keen to skive off work. So I went to
真想偷懒溜走。于是我去
chat to Meg. Jerry's wife was an artist
和梅格聊天。杰瑞的妻子本身就是一位艺术家，
in her own right and had known the map
而且她比
longer than almost anyone. Heads up PMG
几乎所有人都更了解这张地图。PMG的
audience, from this point we're not
观众朋友们注意了，从现在开始，在地图完成之前，我们不会再
going to show you wide shots of the map
展示任何地图
in progress until it's done.
搭建过程中的全景照片。
&gt;&gt; I love that it's always changing. This
我喜欢它一直在变化。这张
map is completely different from any
地图和
other installation we've ever done
我们以往做的任何装置都完全不同，
because this is now.
因为它代表了当下。
&gt;&gt; I see it as very organic.
我觉得它非常自然。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, 100%.
没错，百分之百。
&gt;&gt; Like especially because it looks like
尤其因为它看起来像……
you know, it looks like something that
你知道，它看起来像
grows in a petri dish.
培养皿里生长的东西。
&gt;&gt; I think of it as
我把它想象成
&gt;&gt; [music]
人工智能、气候变化、
Donald Trump, the Ukraine war.
唐纳德·特朗普和乌克兰战争的结合体。
&gt;&gt; Okay.
好吧。就像把
&gt;&gt; It's like blowing [music] up.
音乐炸开一样。
&gt;&gt; I see the climate change. I see the
我看到了气候变化。我看到了
erosion of cities.
城市的衰败。
The Ukraine war. I mean, I know you had
乌克兰战争。我的意思是，我知道你
to introduce violence to it a while back
之前必须把暴力元素融入其中，
and that's what the void represents.
而虚空就代表着暴力。
&gt;&gt; represents, yeah.
代表着，是的。
&gt;&gt; Also, what grows in the void? What
还有，虚空中生长的是什么？
follows is like
接下来就像
&gt;&gt; I know. Is a petri dish.
我知道的那样。是一个培养皿。是
&gt;&gt; [music]
的，是血。是的。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah. So when you talk about like AI,
。所以当你谈到人工智能、
Trump, Ukraine, climate change
特朗普、乌克兰、气候变化时，
&gt;&gt; Nobody knows what's going to happen with
没有人知道
on in our world at this point.
在这个世界正在发生的这些重大变化中，最终会发生什么。
And Jerry, in my mind, Jerry's map at
在我看来，杰瑞，杰瑞此刻的地图
this point is sort [music] of expressing
某种程度上表达了
unrest in our minds about the future.
我们对未来的不安。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, you can't make a map that's just
是的，你不能画一张只有
cities, rivers, and old society. It has
城市、河流和旧社会的地图。它
to reflect
必须反映出
&gt;&gt; plan it like this. That was a complete
规划，就像这样。 这。这完全是……事情
That has just been things set in motion
只是
through the cards, but this is the
通过卡牌启动的，但这却是
result.
结果。
&gt;&gt; It really is antithetical to like where
这确实与
society's going in the internet and
社会在互联网和
productivity.
生产力方面的发展方向背道而驰。
&gt;&gt; Absolutely. And we've always enjoyed
绝对是。我们一直很享受
being [music] in that lane.
在这个领域里做音乐。
&gt;&gt; What's your favorite part of the map?
你最喜欢地图的哪一部分？
&gt;&gt; Oh, god.
哦，天哪。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; I I mourn often [music]
我经常为
the map parts of the map.
地图的消失而感到惋惜。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
distress when I see that the original
当我看到原始
panel
面板被虚空
&gt;&gt; has been half eaten.
吞噬了一半时，我感到既如释重负又痛苦不堪。被
&gt;&gt; is half eaten by the void?
虚空吞噬了一半？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; You can't destroy that.
你无法摧毁它。
&gt;&gt; I know. I know.
我知道。我知道。
&gt;&gt; And he kind of didn't.
而且他也没真的摧毁它。
&gt;&gt; Yeah, exactly. He nibbled at it, but um
是的，没错。他只是浅尝辄止，但……
phase, I would say.
我想说，我尊重并热爱地图的每一个阶段。
But I
但我
sometimes mourn the changes.
有时也会为这些变化而感到惋惜。
&gt;&gt; What do you think the map says about
你认为这张地图反映了
Jerry?
杰瑞的什么特质？
&gt;&gt; He has always been this extraordinary
他一直是一个非凡的
combo, which is one reason [music] I
组合体，这也是我
fell in love with him,
爱上他的原因之一，左右
of right and left brain.
脑兼备。
&gt;&gt; Mhm.
嗯。
&gt;&gt; And his systematized
还有他的 系统化的
brain can come up with these coordinates
大脑可以推导出这些坐标
and the the whole structure of the map,
和整张地图的结构，
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; and yet he tosses it away because he's
但他却把它扔掉，因为他
willing to take chances.
愿意冒险。
I love that about him.
我喜欢他这一点。
It also drives me crazy.
这也让我抓狂。是
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
啊。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声] 是
&gt;&gt; I mean, it's honest. We've been married
我的意思是，这很坦诚。我们结婚
for 44 years, you know.
44年了，你知道。
&gt;&gt; 44 years, it's good going.
44年，还不错。是
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
啊。
&gt;&gt; Um
嗯，
&gt;&gt; I think we'll kind of stay in this for a
我想我们还会继续这样下去
little while longer.
一段时间。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; All right, we've just eaten lunch and um
好了，我们刚吃完午饭，嗯，
I ate too big of a sandwich
我三明治吃得太大了，
and now I can't bend over anymore. So,
现在弯不下腰了。所以，现在正是
this is a good time for me to talk to
我跟
you about my favorite place in the map.
你聊聊地图上我最喜欢的地方的好时机。
Allow me to introduce you to the town of
让我来介绍一下斯塔利镇，
which is Meg's second name. Staly has
这是梅格的中间名。斯塔利
got it all. Staly has some really nice
应有尽有。斯塔利有一些非常漂亮的
screen printing. This is a collaboration
丝网印刷作品。这是
between Meg and Jerry. We have really
梅格和杰瑞的合作作品。我们有很多非常
nice Romanesque screen printing. We have
漂亮的罗马式丝网印刷作品。我们有
a lot of these old city sections which
很多老城区的图案，
have mostly been destroyed now, but you
现在大部分都已经被摧毁了，但是……
can still see it's a [music] town. I
仍然能看出这是个音乐小镇。我
like to imagine that I live in Staly.
喜欢想象自己住在斯塔利。
We've got a lovely like bay. We've got
我们有个美丽的海湾。我们有……
flight Where's my stick?
我的棍子在哪儿？
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
（笑）
&gt;&gt; I need a stick to
我需要一根棍子……
Huh.
嗯。
We've got an airport. We've got flight
我们有个机场。我们有
lines. We've got all this water which
跑道。我们还有一大片水域，但
immediately becomes really dark and
很快就变得非常黑暗和
ominous. What do the people of Staly see
不祥。斯塔利的人们
on the other side of the water? They see
在水的另一边看到了什么？他们看到了
the void and then like horrible horrific
虚空，然后是可怕的
red dimension stuff and and then behind
红色维度，在
the red dimension there's a ziggurat.
红色维度的后面是一座金字形神塔。
There is also, I love this. This is
还有，我喜欢这个。这是
something Jerry used to do, but then
杰瑞以前做过的事情，但后来
faded from the deck.
从甲板上消失了。
But, Jerry used to build public
杰瑞过去常常建造公共
infrastructure. That's a wall designed
基础设施。这是一堵用来
to keep the void away. And you can see
阻挡虚空的墙。你可以
some places in the map where these walls
在地图上看到一些地方，这些墙
still hold. So, the town of Staly has
仍然屹立不倒。所以，斯塔利镇有一个类似
this like kind of bleak failed civic
凄凉的失败的市政
project to hold back the void which is
工程，用来阻挡从
coming in in the wrong places and it's
错误的地方涌入的虚空，
like
就像……
This is a this is like a this is a
这就像…… 这是一个
locate This is a place. Really speaks to
地点。这是一个地方。它真的触动了
me.
我。
And Jerry's probably going to destroy
而杰瑞很可能会毁了
it.
它。我
&gt;&gt; Preemptively mourning the township of
提前为斯塔利镇哀悼
Staly, I went to get some air with its
，然后去和它的
executioner.
刽子手透透气。
Do you like [music] the map?
你喜欢这张地图吗？
&gt;&gt; I love the map.
我喜欢这张地图。
&gt;&gt; When do you love it the most?
你什么时候最喜欢它？
&gt;&gt; When it's there in my hands and I'm
当它在我手里，我
patching it and I'm
修补它，我
changing it and then now I I'm I pretty
修改它的时候。现在我已经和以前那个我完全
detached from [music] that animal that I
脱离了
was before.
。
&gt;&gt; you haven't seen it laid out for 14
你已经14年没见过它展开的样子了
years.
没错。
&gt;&gt; Right.
所以，
you as we're laying it out?
当我们展开它的时候，这对你来说有点意外吗？
&gt;&gt; is.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Really?
真的吗？
&gt;&gt; When you lay it out?
当你展开它的时候？
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Are you looking at at it and then
你看着它，然后
thinking, [music]
想，“
"Oh, I need to change the deck. There's
哦，我需要换个甲板。”  “
too much of this." or
这太多了。”或者“
&gt;&gt; Yes. Yeah. Yeah, that's the great the
是的。没错。没错，这就是这种
positive impact of a display like this
展览对我而言最大的积极影响。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; It's not showing it to people. It's
这不是把它展示给别人看，而是让我
being like, "Oh, I need to change this."
意识到，“哦，我需要改变一下。”
about my process.
关于我的创作过程。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
these days.
最近我不太喜欢这种空白。
&gt;&gt; Really? Even even the second layer of
真的吗？即使是空白的第二层，也
the void where it's your receipts and
就是你的收据和
your
你的……
&gt;&gt; That's better. I wish there were more of
这样好多了。我希望有
more void cities developing.
更多空白之城正在形成。
&gt;&gt; Turns out the these huge
结果发现，这些
massive swaths of destroyed art actually
大片被毁坏的艺术品其实
doesn't feel that good.
感觉并不好。
&gt;&gt; No. [music]
不。[音乐]
&gt;&gt; That's what I've been saying.
这就是我一直说的。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; That's what I've been saying for days is
我这几天一直在说，
like, "Oh boy, you sure erased a lot of
就像，“哦，天哪，你肯定抹掉了好多
this." And then now you see it laid out
东西。” 然后现在你看到它们摆在那里，
and you're like, "Oh yeah, that is bad."
你会想，“哦，是的，这很糟糕。” 是
&gt;&gt; Yeah. [laughter]
的。[笑声]
&gt;&gt; The void
空白，
&gt;&gt; my ways. Come back in 10 years. I
我的方式。10年后再来。我
guarantee
保证。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; will be filled in and come out. See,
会被填满，然后显现出来。你看，
that's what I was
我当时也是这样，
&gt;&gt; I'm also sick of the red dimension.
我也厌倦了红色维度。
I'm sick of it.
我厌倦了。
&gt;&gt; I was looking at the map for the last
过去几天我一直在看那张地图，
few days and when I see the void and
当我看到虚空，
when I see you weaving ephemera from
当我看到你把生活中的点点滴滴编织
your life through it, the emails, the
进去，那些邮件、
receipts, [music]
收据、[音乐]，
you know, photographs. Um, I saw a lot
你知道的，照片。嗯，我
of mortality in the map. I saw I saw
在地图上看到了很多死亡的意象。我看到了
death and we talked about how you're
死亡，我们讨论过你是如何
trying to take these things instead of
试图接受这些东西，而不是
trying to save them. And so to me it
试图保存它们。所以对我来说，
initially [music]
最初[音乐]
it felt like it was about legacy. And
感觉像是关于传承。
then I had the most amazing conversation
然后我
with your wife where she said she didn't
和你妻子进行了一次非常棒的谈话，她说她完全不
quite see it that way at all. She said
这么认为。她说，
that when you turn 70 years old you've
当你70岁的时候，你
spent your whole life looking forward at
的一生都在展望
what's coming next. But then you arrive
未来。但当你到达一个
at this wonderful moment like cresting a
美妙的时刻，就像登上
hill where suddenly you can look
山顶，突然间你可以
backwards. And you can get all this
回头看。你可以
richness and joy from looking in reverse
从回望过去，
and seeing the whole life.
看到整个人生，获得所有丰富的和喜悦。
And so she said the the map wasn't about
所以她说 这张地图并非关乎
mortality. It's actually a reflection.
死亡。它实际上是一种反思。
It's like a diary on a life well lived.
它就像一本记录美好人生的日记。
&gt;&gt; Well, it works both ways. Right?
嗯，它是双向的，对吧？
Um, yes. It it's um
嗯，是的。
it's revisiting the past
它是对过去的回顾，
and then and savoring those moments.
然后细细品味那些时刻。
And over my shoulder, you know,
而我的背后，你知道，
is what's coming.
是未来。
Wait, for me what that does is it
等等，对我来说，它的作用是给
it puts pressure on me to
我施加压力，让我
go faster.
走得更快。
&gt;&gt; To go faster?
走得更快？
&gt;&gt; And do more. Yes.
做得更多。是的。
&gt;&gt; Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
&gt;&gt; Because
因为
&gt;&gt; Some would say you've [music] done quite
有些人会说你已经做了很多（音乐）
a lot already.
。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Come back in 10 years and
十年后再回来，
uh
嗯，
&gt;&gt; I love that. How would you feel
我喜欢这个说法。
if after you've passed someone close to
如果你去世后，你身边的人
you wanted to continue working on the
想要继续完善这张
map?
地图，你会作何感想？
&gt;&gt; That would be cool.
那会很酷。
As a matter of fact, I
事实上，就
pretty recently, in the last couple of
在最近
weeks, [music] had fantasies of oh, I
几周，我（音乐）幻想过，我
could give
可以给
an artist like 20 [music] panels
一位艺术家20个（音乐）面板，
and say, "Okay, this is the seed. Just
然后说：“好的，这是种子。” 就
take it from there. And go wherever you
从这里开始吧。  “你想去哪儿就去哪儿
want."
。”
&gt;&gt; You know what that reminds me of? When a
你知道这让我想起了什么吗？当
tree falls in the forest, it is an
森林里的一棵树倒下时，它会
release of energy out into the
向周围环境释放出难以想象的能量
environment. That the amount of insects
。无数的昆虫
and small life forms that feast on it
和小生物以它为食，然后繁殖，
and then breed and then spread. Like it
然后扩散。就像
if this enormous oak tree were to fall,
如果一棵巨大的橡树倒下，就会
that you would then create seeds and
产生种子和
energy for artists everywhere to
能量，让世界各地的艺术家
continue working on the same ecosystem.
继续在同一个生态系统中创作。
&gt;&gt; You know that there is a
你知道有一个
a subreddit called Jerry Mapping.
叫“Jerry Mapping”的Reddit子版块吗？
&gt;&gt; Oh, Jerry Mapping?
哦，Jerry Mapping？
&gt;&gt; Jerry Mapping. Yes. And it was devoted
Jerry Mapping。是的。它是专门讨论那些以Jerry Gretzinger
to people who do mapping in the style of
风格进行地图绘制的人的
Jerry Gretzinger. People are intrigued
。人们
with the with the idea, but their
对这个想法很感兴趣，但他们的
interpretations are there totally
解读却截然不同
different.
。
&gt;&gt; I mean, Jerry Mapping it
我的意思是，“Jerry Mapping”这个
it's it's a wonderful word. It's like
词很棒。就像“
Jerry rigging, right?
Jerry rigging”（临时搭建），对吧？
&gt;&gt; Yeah, or Jerrymandering.
是的，或者“Jerrymandering”（操纵选区）。
&gt;&gt; Oh, no.
哦，不。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; By the end of day two, we'd laid over
到第二天结束时，我们已经铺设了超过
3,000
3000块
panels, which meant it was almost time
面板，这意味着差不多该结束了。
to say goodbye to the Great Lakes, to
向五大湖、
the map, and to Jerry and Meg.
地图，还有杰瑞和梅格说再见。
Fortunately, we had another 1,000 panels
幸运的是，我们还有1000块面板可以
to distract us. It's day three. Let's
分散注意力。今天是第三天。加油！
Every project is going to, you know,
你知道，每个项目都会
encounter some hurdles as people get
遇到一些障碍，因为人们会感到
tired. Um these are my colleagues today.
疲惫。嗯，这些是我今天的同事。
Um how much did you two drink yesterday?
嗯，你们俩昨天喝了多少？
&gt;&gt; One glass of wine.
一杯葡萄酒。
&gt;&gt; One glass of wine?
一杯葡萄酒？
&gt;&gt; Three.
三。
&gt;&gt; One, three.
一，三。
&gt;&gt; Bottles.
瓶。
&gt;&gt; I heard I heard one box of wine and then
我听说，我听说，一箱葡萄酒，然后是
several bottles. And what I would like
几瓶。我想
to know is how many panels have you two
知道的是，你们俩
installed upside down in the last hour?
在过去一个小时里装反了多少块面板？
&gt;&gt; Five, six.
五，六。
&gt;&gt; Interesting.
有意思。
That's not That's not my count at all.
这根本不是我的统计。
&gt;&gt; You can't you you had a margarita last
你不能说你昨晚喝了玛格丽塔
night.
。
&gt;&gt; Yes. And how many mistakes have I made?
是的。那我犯了多少错误？
One, because these two are putting me
一个，因为这两个家伙太烦人了，让我很恼火。别这样
Don't talk to me like
跟我说话。
&gt;&gt; As we entered the final hours of the
在我们进入施工的最后几个小时时
build, Jerry offered me one last glimpse
，杰瑞让我最后一次瞥了一眼
at [music] the mother of all rule books.
[音乐]——所有规则手册之母。
&gt;&gt; Somebody, I I think it was on Reddit
有人，我想 Reddit 上有人
said, "Oh, this is [music] an analog
说：“哦，这是[音乐]一件模拟
generative art piece."
生成艺术作品。” 是的
&gt;&gt; Yes.
。是的。是的。是的
Yes. Yes. Yes. But, it's one where
。但是，
usually with generative art pieces or
通常来说，生成艺术作品或
with digital generation you are creating
数字生成作品都是你创造
a a a machine and then it creates the
一台机器，然后它生成
piece of art.
艺术作品。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Right.
没错。对。
&gt;&gt; But, you are running the engine,
但是，你是在启动引擎，
stopping the engine, making a change,
停止引擎，进行修改，再
running the engine, stopping, making a
启动引擎，停止引擎，再进行
change.
修改。
&gt;&gt; Right.
对。对
&gt;&gt; Right. [music] As we neared completion,
。[音乐] 随着作品接近完成，
the room was abuzz with anticipation.
房间里充满了期待的气氛。
Even the local press turned up. Their
甚至当地媒体也来了。说
cameras were, honestly, a bit bigger
实话，他们的相机
than ours, and that's fine.
比我们的大得多，这没关系。
This was it. The map was nearly
就是它了。地图几乎
complete. And when we had just one panel
完成了。当只剩最后一块面板时，
left we gave it to Jerry to do the
我们把它交给了杰瑞来
honors.
揭幕。
&gt;&gt; Woo!
哇！
&gt;&gt; [cheering]
[欢呼声]
&gt;&gt; Ah.
啊。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; It was a breathtaking [music]
这是一个令人叹为观止的[音乐]
installation. I hope that comes across
装置。我希望
on camera. It's this fabulous
镜头能捕捉到这一点。它是一片绚丽多彩的
technicolor expanse.
景象。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; But, for us who built it, it was
但对我们这些建造者来说，它的意义却有所不同
something else. Because our experience
。因为我们的经历
of this art wasn't just visual. It was
这件艺术作品不仅仅是视觉上的，它也是
physical. We'd built this on our knees
身体上的。我们跪在地上，
with a community watching it emerge
和一群人一起，看着它一块一块
strip by strip, piece by piece, spotting
、一小块地逐渐成形，发现
new secrets and sharing them with one
新的秘密，并彼此分享
another. But also watching the panels
。但我们也看着
we'd fallen in love with yesterday
昨天还让我们心动的那些面板渐渐
receding into the distance. We had
消失在远方。我们和
Jerry and Meg and so many others. And
杰瑞、梅格以及其他许多人一起探索了这片土地。然后，
blasphemous, Jerry invited us to take
杰瑞做了一件近乎亵渎的事情：他邀请我们
off our shoes and walk into the map with
脱掉鞋子，和他一起走进地图
him.
。
You know there's the question with art
你知道，艺术作品总会面临一个问题，那就是
of like how close should you stand to
应该离它多近
&gt;&gt; Oh, yeah.
。哦，对了，
&gt;&gt; It's This is unfortunate for the people
这对后来者来说可能有点遗憾，
coming later, but I think the best way
但我认为
to absorb this map is to be in it and
欣赏这张地图的最佳方式就是置身其中，
walking through it.
穿梭其中。
&gt;&gt; I had a fantasy once
我曾经幻想过，把
of showing the map
地图
upside down
倒过来，
about 4 ft off the floor
离地面大约4英尺，
with people on rolling boards.
让人们站在滑板上。
&gt;&gt; So they're on those mechanics boards and
他们拿着手电筒，站在那些滑板上，抬头
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and they're looking up at That way
看着地图。这样，他们就
they'd always be 4 ft from it.
始终离地图4英尺远。
&gt;&gt; Oh. Oh.
哦，哦。
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
是的。
&gt;&gt; Oh, wow.
哦，哇。
&gt;&gt; That That requires some other
那需要一些其他的
&gt;&gt; engineering, yeah.
工程技术，下次再说。
&gt;&gt; So no part of you looks at this and
所以你看着这个，绝对不会
thinks that's enough.
觉得够了。
&gt;&gt; No, no, no.
不，不，不。
&gt;&gt; No.
不。
&gt;&gt; You look
你看着
&gt;&gt; I I I get concerned I'm moving more
我，我开始担心我的动作
slowly. My hands are not
变慢了。我的手……
Oops, I'm sorry, guys.
哎呀，对不起，各位。
I I'll just I
我……
&gt;&gt; I'm sure it's important.
我确定这很重要。
&gt;&gt; It's Meg.
是梅格。
&gt;&gt; take it.
接吧。
&gt;&gt; Hello there. You're calling I'm standing
你好。你打电话来，我正站在
in the middle of the map and they're
地图中间，他们正在
filming me and all of this is on camera
拍摄我，这一切都被摄像机
and
和
microphone.
麦克风拍下来了。
&gt;&gt; Are you drinking water?
你在喝水吗？
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; I think she's calling to ask if I'm
我想她打电话来是问我有没有
drinking water.
喝水。
You know,
你知道，
you called me and asked me that last
你上次打电话来问我这个问题，
time and I swore I was going to go out
我发誓我要去
to the lobby and have some water and I
大厅喝点水，但我
didn't do it.
没去。
somebody to get you water.
有人给你拿水。
&gt;&gt; Okay. Yes. Yes. I have three witnesses.
好的。是的。是的。我有三个证人。好的。好的。好的，特鲁迪。
Okay. Okay. All right, Trudy. All right.
好的。
Okay. Bye.
好的。再见。
&gt;&gt; We did in fact make sure Jerry got some
我们确实确保杰瑞喝到了水。
water, which he'd need because for the
他需要一些水，因为
first time in 14 years, for one night
14年来，
only, the map was to be exhibited to the
这张地图将首次公开展出，而且仅此一晚
public.
。
And Jerry, he seemed happy to share his
杰瑞似乎很乐意
world with us, but it was clear that not
与我们分享他的世界，但很明显，
only was this thing not finished, it
这不仅还没完成，而且也不是
wasn't really for us. It was the process
为了我们。真正
that compelled him. We were just
吸引他的是创作的过程。我们只是幸运的
bystanders who'd been lucky enough to
旁观者，有幸
meet him and his map on their epic
在他们共同的史诗之旅中遇见了他和他的地图
journey together.
。
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐] 大家
&gt;&gt; Hello, this is Chris here back in the UK
好，我是克里斯，现在回到了英国。
now and I thought you might like to join
我想你们可能想和
me as I go to get this framed. So, Jerry
我一起去把这张地图裱起来。杰瑞真是个
being the absolute sweetheart he is
好人，
gifted me one of his cards as we left
离开密歇根的时候送了我一张他的牌
Michigan. It's been retired from his
。这张牌已经从他的
deck and has number 36 on which you can
牌组中退役了，上面有数字36，你们可以
see there and a couple of rules as well.
看到，还有几条规则。
One says new color, I understand that
一条写着“新颜色”，我明白；
and then one says [music]
另一条写着[音乐]“
population two which will, frankly,
人口2”，坦白说，
I don't. Anyways, you can probably tell
我不明白。总之，你们现在大概也能看出，
by now this was by some distance the
这绝对是
most ambitious documentary People Make
People Make
Games has ever produced. It required
Games迄今为止制作的最雄心勃勃的纪录片。
myself and Quinns to travel over to the
我和奎因斯不得不前往
States to spend a week with Jerry, Meg
美国，和杰瑞、梅格
and their family. We worked with another
以及他们的家人待了一周。我们还和那边的另一位
camera operator over there as well.
摄影师合作。特别
Shout out to Alex. We needed his drone.
感谢亚历克斯，我们需要他的无人机。
We did time lapses. Then there's the
我们拍摄了延时摄影。然后，还有
logistics of constructing this thing at
在堡垒中心搭建这个展品的后勤工作，
the Stronghold Center and all the
以及所有
volunteers and the exhibit. That's not
志愿者和展览的安排。这还不
to mention everything that's happened
包括在家里发生的一切
back home, the planning, the edit,
，策划、剪辑、
[music] all of the things that Annie has
配乐等等，安妮几个月来一直在努力完成的所有事情
been chipping away at for months. This
。这对
was a big, big swing for us, and we came
我们来说是一次巨大的尝试，但我们最终带回了大量令人
back with just the most incredible
难以置信的
treasure trove of footage to share with
珍贵素材，想和
you all. Hold that thought, let me just
大家分享。等等，让我
pop in here.
插一句。
I I think that's that's the one. Yeah,
我想就是这个。对，就是
&gt;&gt; [music]
配上音乐的那个。好的。
&gt;&gt; I think that's really nice.
我觉得这个很棒。
&gt;&gt; Cool. It is really nice. Anyway, while
酷。确实很棒。总之，在
filming this documentary, we found
拍摄这部纪录片的过程中，我们发现
ourselves in an interesting [music]
自己陷入了一个有趣的音乐
situation where first of all, we've
困境，首先，我们花在制作
spent more money making this thing than
这部纪录片上的钱比
I think we've ever spent on one single
我们以往花在……上的钱都多。
project before now. And we also got back
此前我们只做过一个项目。而且，我们
from Michigan with just all of this
从密歇根州回来的时候，还带回了很多
additional lovely footage that couldn't
精彩的额外素材，可惜最终没
make its way
能用
&gt;&gt; [music]
在正片里。
in order to create an exclusive
为了解决这两个问题，我们和Nebula合作，他们赞助了这部纪录片，共同制作了一部独家
companion video that's going to sit
配套视频。
alongside this piece featuring some
这部视频将与正片一同发布，其中包含
Quinn's and Jerry, a look inside Meg's
Quinn和Jerry的一些精彩片段，Meg的工作室内部探访（
[music] own studio where she tells us
她会讲述
about the fashion business that she and
她和
her husband used to run together, and a
丈夫曾经共同经营的时尚事业），以及其他
whole range of stuff, actually. [music]
各种各样的内容。
And that video is available to watch
这部视频现在就可以观看了
right now, today. To do so, you'll want
。观看方法是
to head over to Nebula, which as many of
前往Nebula，相信很多人都
you will know by now is a streaming
知道，Nebula是一个流媒体
[music] platform that's home to loads of
音乐平台，汇聚了许多
interesting, thoughtful creators like
有趣且富有创意的音乐人，比如
Lindsay Ellis, Tom Nicholas, FD [music]
Lindsay Ellis、Tom Nicholas、FD
Signifier, Jacob Geller, loads of folks.
Signifier、Jacob Geller等等。在
And over there you can watch all of
那里，你可以观看
their videos entirely [music] ad-free,
他们所有的视频。  Nebula 完全无广告，
and Nebula has also increasingly become
而且越来越
a place that's interested in supporting
倾向于支持
more ambitious, sometimes quite
更具雄心、有时
expensive video work, which is why
成本也相当高的视频作品。正因如此，
they've stepped in to help us fund this
他们才出手帮助我们资助这部
documentary we just had to make about a
关于一位
man and [music] his map. It's also why
男士及其地图的纪录片。
if you're a Philosophy Tube fan, for
例如，如果你是 Philosophy Tube 的粉丝，
example, you'll know that she was able
你就会知道她
to team up with Nebula to film an
与 Nebula 合作，拍摄了
exquisite live performance of her
她莎士比亚戏剧《王子》的精彩现场演出。
on youtube.com alone, let me tell you.
我可以告诉你，这在 YouTube 上是很难实现的。
We publish all of PNG's videos over on
我们已经在 Nebula 上发布了 PNG 的所有视频，而且
Nebula already, without ads, as do
没有广告，
hundreds of other creators. And many of
其他数百位创作者也是如此。
them are now making exclusive videos
他们中的许多人现在也在那里制作独家视频
[music] over there as well, like this
，比如
companion piece of ours that you can
我们
watch today. If you use our link,
今天发布的这部作品。如果你使用我们的链接
go.nebula.tv/peoplemakegames,
go.nebula.tv/peoplemakegames，
you'll be able to access a healthy
你就能享受
discount to the Nebula subscription,
Nebula 订阅的超值折扣。
[music] slashing the annual sub in half.
年度订阅费减半。
If you're in the UK, for example, that
例如，如果您身处英国，这
means instead of paying [music] £60 per
意味着您无需每年支付 60 英镑
year, you'll pay just 30, which works
，只需支付 30 英镑，
out at £2.50 per month. And that same
相当于每月 2.50 英镑。同样的
deal exists in USD or in euros or in a
优惠也适用于美元、欧元以及
bunch of other currencies. [music] And
其他多种货币。
to be blunt, PMG gets a cut of any
坦白说，PMG 会从每笔
sign-up, so if you do end up going over
注册中抽取一部分佣金，所以如果您最终选择注册
there, you'll be supporting [music] us
，您实际上是
directly in the process. When Quinn
在直接支持我们。当 Quinn
first pitched his story to us, we wanted
最初向我们讲述他的故事时，我们就想把
to do it right. In this case, that meant
它做好。在这种情况下，这意味着我们需要
bringing in the extra funding to make it
额外的资金，才能以
happen [music] in the way that we felt
我们认为
this documentary deserved. And so,
这部纪录片应有的方式完成它。因此，
consider this, I guess, a bit of a test
我想，这可以看作是一个测试
case for just how ambitious [music] we
案例，检验
when the right opportunity presents
当合适的时机出现时，我们讲述的故事究竟能有多大的野心
itself. Collaborating with Nebula like
。与 Nebula 这样的合作使得我们能够
all in on the idea, and hey, it's also
全力以赴地投入到这个想法中，而且，嘿，这也……
meant, I think, that we've also created
我的意思是，我们还制作了
a really nice extra video that some of
一个非常棒的额外视频，
you are going to really [music] enjoy.
你们中的一些人一定会非常喜欢。
look at that.
瞧瞧！
&gt;&gt; Thank you for joining us on this one. We
感谢你们收看本期节目。我们非常非常
have just been so, so happy to have met
高兴能认识
Jerry and his map and his family and to
杰瑞、他的地图和他的家人，并在
have shared this story here on this
这个频道上分享这个故事。
channel, where I hope we've kind of
我希望我们能
continued to stretch out the definition
继续拓展
of what we mean when we think about
我们对
people making games. Sometimes, it looks
游戏制作人的定义。有时候，它看起来确实有点像
even a little bit like that. Thank you
那样。感谢
for watching, and we will see you next
收看，我们下次再见
time. Oh, also, stick around for the
。哦，对了，别忘了看
credits, cuz they're quite fun.
片尾字幕，因为它们很有趣。
&gt;&gt; I know you said
我知道你们都喊了“
&gt;&gt; Yay!
耶！
Woohoo!
呜呼！耶！呜！
&gt;&gt; [applause]
耶！”
&gt;&gt; Sounds pretty good.
[掌声]
&gt;&gt; [music]
[音乐]
&gt;&gt; Is it done?
完成了吗？
&gt;&gt; Moving on.
下一个。算是吧。永远
&gt;&gt; It's never done.
没有完成的时候。
It looks good.
看起来不错。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Oh, no. All right, I have to do better
哦，不。好吧，我得做得更好
than that.
。
This is what working for Jerry is like.
这就是为杰瑞工作的感觉。
&gt;&gt; [laughter]
[笑声]
&gt;&gt; Let's go Let's go on the
走吧，走吧，
Oh my god, that was amazing.
我的天哪， 太棒了。